The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Depths of the Tide Abyss
Si She\NDa Lou Sword Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
Xu Gou\NDa Lou Sword Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
You Ji\NDa Lou Sword Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
Senior Brother !
Senior Brother...
Senior Greed,
Chen Long\NDa Lou Sword Sect disciple\NEarly stage Ascendant
it's impossible to drive away
these demonic beasts with my limited strength.
Junior beg you to do something
to get us out of this place !
Greed\NPeak Late stage Ascendant\N(Originally Illusory Yin)
Junior Brother Shen Hou
was killed by those beasts the day before yesterday.
Since Senior remains so unmoved...
Is it possible that...
you're unafraid of betraying Master's trust !?
Little brats...
For the sake of your Master,
this old man will forgive your disrespect.
But if you do it again...
The Tide Abyss
doesn't only pull in artifacts from the starry sky.
All kinds of ferocious demonic beasts
were also pulled in here.
At the bottom of this abyss,
the beasts that were able to survive that environment
are entities even I am unwilling to provoke.
Wu Ma\NDa Lou Sword Sect disciple\NPeak Late stage Soul Transformation
If you guys dare to rush in blindly,
it's a direct path to your deaths.
Forgive us, Senior.
But we have been trapped here by these beasts
for 100 years already.
Are you in a rush ?
In another 100 years,
Ling Tianhou will personally come to save us.
This journey is secret
so no one in the Demon Spirit Land knows our whereabouts.
The safest place to wait is right here.
6 entrances
but only a single exit.
Tide Abyss Exit\NFire Demon Country
Senior Zhou Yi
is beneath this Tide Abyss.
This restriction isn't for killing
but for gathering information.
Greed has a profound cultivation,
I must stay on guard.
Tide Abyss Entrance\NWater Demon Country
Brother Murong,
Junior Sisters,
Du Jian\NHeavenly Fate Sect Red Division disciple\NPeak Late stage Soul Transformation
this is the place.
I've studied the Tide Abyss for decades
to finally find this entrance.
If we enter together,
we're sure to have a great harvest.
Murong Zhuo\NPlanet Tian Yun's Ink Sect disciple\NEarly stage Ascendant
The person arriving
is very strong.
Junior Brother Wang, please wait !
Junior Brother Wang,
I am Du Jian of the Red Division.
This is Murong Zhuo from the Ink Sect.
These two are from the Floating Cloud Sect.
Senior Brother Wang,
Zhao Yixuan\NFloating Cloud Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
I am Zhao Yixuan.
This is my Junior Sister, Xu Fei.
Xu Fei\NFloating Cloud Sect disciple\NLate stage Soul Transformation
Xu Fei ?
Note: Xu Fei was a disciple of the Heng Yue Sect we only saw in episode 4.
Junior Brother Wang,
is it possible that you have a history with Junior Sister Xu ?
I don't know her.
It's just that Junior Sister Xu
has the same name
as someone I knew in my youth.
So Junior Brother Wang is also here for the Tide Abyss.
Why don't we travel together
to face the dangers together ?
What do you think ?
He's merely native from a wasted cultivation planet.
But back then,
he almost became one of the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
If we let him grow,
I'm afraid that we, his Senior Brothers,
will never have a chance to rise again.
This person was able to detect me in advance.
He is not simple.
These women from the Floating Cloud Sect
also have something indescribably wrong about them.
Agreed.
Then let's go.
The abyss is filled with danger
but I can use their strength
to scout this place.
If they have ill-intent,
I'll just kill them.
Everyone,
there are treasures all around the place.
We shall each rely on our own abilities
to search for them.
Call for help when in danger.
As expected, it's a one-way restriction.
If someone were to force it,
I'm afraid they would be crushed by the laws of this place.
It seems the only way to leave is indeed through the exit in the Fire Demon Country.
Demonic beasts all around...
Interconnected caves...
Truly worthy of being a thousands of years old treasure abyss.
Fortunately, I have the jade slip gifted by the Ancient Demon
to help me find my way.
To rescue Senior Zhou Yi,
I need to take my time
and plan accordingly.
1 day later
Everyone,
follow me.
Ancient Tree\NTide Abyss
It's right there.
The Tian Yun Sword !
This sword
is one of the 7 swords of Master All-Seer.
They were given to the Seven Sons of Tian Yun as guardian artifacts.
However, over the countless years,
3 of them went missing with their owners.
Junior Brother Sun Yun of the Purple Division
disappeared back then while carrying this sword.
Brother Murong,
Junior Sister Zhao,
Junior Sister Xu,
this sword belongs to the Heavenly Fate Sect.
Today,
I, Du Jian,
need to ask you a favor.
How about
we let Junior Brother Wang take this sword ?
He's a disciple of the Purple Division of our Heavenly Fate Sect.
Giving him the sword
is like returning it to its original owner.
Junior Brother Wang,
this sword
originally belonged to your Purple Division.
Senior Brother won't steal it
and I won't let anyone else steal it either !
Senior Brother Du is very virtuous.
This tree isn't normal.
Fellow cultivator Wang, be careful.
This Murong Zhuo
does have some skill.
Charge !
Is the Tian Yun Sword Senior Brother spoke of
this pile of scrap iron ?
I...
I was mistaken.
How could Senior Brother Du, who has studied the Tide Abyss for decades
be mistaken ?
Do you see clearly now ?
This tree is an illusion of poisonous insects.
You...
how did you see through it !?
We've only just met
but Senior Brother Du turns out to be an hypocrite.
Given our relationship,
how can we even be called brothers ?
Since you tried to trap me,
you should've expected the consequences as well.
Everyone,
let's continue.
Cliff\NTide Abyss
This is the 37th type of beast we encountered.
This poison is already 3 times
more concentrated than at the entrance.
So that's how it is...
I have private matters to attend to
so I won't be going down with you.
Brother Murong,
if you ever need me in the future,
don't hesitate.
Brother Wang, if you need anything in the future,
please do the same.
Be careful of the two women beside you.
If I'm not mistaken,
they should be from the Corpse Sect.
One is the Corpse Puppet
and the other is the true body.
Cliff\NTide Abyss
The place Bei Luo pointed me to
is right here.
But why isn't there any trace of Senior Zhou Yi
or of Ling Tianhou here ?
I'm pretty sure Bei Luo didn't lie to me.
If he wanted to harm me,
he could have just done so.
Even if he wanted to kill me,
he should have tricked me into going to the bottom of the abyss instead.
Where exactly did I go wrong ?
If I were Ling Tianhou...
What would I have done ?
If I wanted to seal a Sword Spirit that was haunting me,
I wouldn’t simply seal it.
I'd restrict it for thousands of years
to make it yield
and submit to my tyranny.
Such a seal would've been
impossible on the surface.
I found it.
Ling Tianhou is a powerful rival of the All-Seer
so he must be at least Late stage Nirvana Cleanser.
Billion-Soul Flag !
Master,
that thing is too strong !
I won't...
be able to hold on !
Go !
Even the Scattered Devil soul couldn't last for a single breath !
God-Slaying Chariot,
activate !
This aura...
could it be ...?
This is...
Ling Tianhou's aura.
The Sword Spirit's seal is well hidden.
How could it have been discovered ?
It's alright.
It's just an ant trying to shake a tree.
It's courting its own death.
A single strike from a strand of his Divine Sense
is actually this powerful...
With my own strength,
it's absolutely impossible to beat with this Divine Sense.
Master, please think twice !
That old ghost is not to be messed with !
I have fought all my life
and seen too much deception.
But one of the only sincere people I met
has instead left me with an obsession
within my Dao.
Back then,
his infatuation made him breakthough to Ascendant.
And I
was just a Soul Formation Junior.
But now,
I have also reached Ascendant.
Because of this karma,
I have charged into this Tide Abyss.
Stop !
Underworld...
River !
I, Wang Lin, live between the heavens and the earth
with an unforgettable obsession.
So what if there are powerful foes ?
So what if I live or die ?
If I were to stay hesitant and overly cautious,
even if I live for 10 000 years,
that life would be in vain ! A meaningless existence !
Now,
I shall use the Celestial Symbols as the foundation
and my Origin Soul as the guide
to seal your Divine Sense, Ling Tianhou !
Master, you mustn't !
If the seal is broken,
your Origin Soul will be heavily injured !
Weighing the pros and cons
is what everyone does.
It's also something I'm very good at.
But this battle is an exception !
No, Master !
Golden Symbol...
Seal !
Now or never !
Senior !
Ask
Qi Condensation
the perilous path filled with countless blades.
Foundation Establishment
Can the mundane world be shattered
Core Formation
Nascent Soul
by a child's steadfast heart ?
If the laws of this world
Soul Formation
Soul Transformation
stand in the way,
I'll defy the universe to tread the heavens
Ascendant
and ask this question to the sky.
My heart's deepest wish
is to not kneel before these mountains and rivers.
Don't accept your doomed fate,
karma can be changed.
Unwilling to let go,
my obsessions propel me forward.
Don't be afraid.
Thunder rumbles as I dare to tread through the reincarnation cycle.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.